Hey, what's up everybody? We're back for
another edition here in the car. Uh, I
want to talk about dealing with regrets.
And this is a topic. It's actually one
of my most watched videos here on
YouTube is dealing with regrets and how
to not let things that don't go how you
want them to fully to derail you or
affect you. I believe listen, we live in
life and situations happen that don't go
how we want. But I think one of the most
powerful things that we can do is to not
live inside of those regrets. Some of
y'all know some of my story and I made
some major mistakes
uh about 15 years ago where I was
drinking a lot of alcohol and uh I had
one instance where I had actually posted
something on social media that got me
arrested because of it was a it was a a
facicious threat that I had made. I was
drunk and it got reported and and and
and honestly I'm glad that the police
responded to it and they took it
seriously and it terrified me and it
taught me such a lesson. Now, yes, I
regret that I did that 100% right. It
was a stupid thing that I did. You would
never see me even come clo like just not
even in the range of what I would do
today as a father and as a business
owner and things like that. This was 15
years ago.
But how have I made peace with the fact
of what happened is that I know that a
it's part of my story and b I know that
if I can share with somebody the lessons
that I've learned along the way that I
don't have to live regretting what
happened. And you might say, "Well, that
sounds great, Jeremiah. You have a great
lesson from that. But what about if you
make a mistake that truly impacts you in
a negative way, like say financially or
something like that?" Well, I'll give
you an example of this. I've actually
had a couple of times where um like I
bought some cryptocurrency and it
dropped in value and I lost money. I
bought a stock and it dropped in value
and I lost money. And the regret that I
felt was so devastating in that moment.
But what I had to do was and and and
full transparency, I love investing. I
love trading. I love the stock market.
It's provided my family with millions of
dollars in in capital that we've been
able to generate by being able to make
good solid investments. But when you're
making investments, you're also going to
lose, especially when you're learning
how to do it. When you're learning
something in your business, you're going
to make mistakes. You're going to mess
up. You're going to do the wrong thing.
It's not always going to work out quote
unquote how you want it to or how it's
supposed to in your mind. And so what we
have to do is we have to make peace with
the fact that stuff happens. Things
don't always go how we want. The
disappointment, the frustration, all of
those things, those are real human
emotions. And I think that it's okay to
feel those emotions. It needs to be okay
to feel those emotions. But then learn
to forgive yourself. learn to move on
quickly. And I think sometimes our need
to control everything, control the
outcome, feel like we're in control and
all of that. Okay. If you if you grew up
in a situation where you were
traumatized and you felt like you
weren't in control in your life, you are
going to crave
whatever you can do to feel in control
to make you feel like, okay, I made this
mistake, but at least I can regain some
sense of control. And yes, controlling
what you can control is great, but
regret regret is living. It's kind of a
form of grief is what it is. Regret is a
form of grief. You're grieving the
version of your life of how you expected
or thought things to go. It creates this
frustration and we can end up living in
it. depending on how bad the regret is,
we end up literally living in a split
identity, a split way of being to where
we're like we have the version of how we
thought things would go and then we have
reality and our regret is literally
controlling our thoughts because we're
like, "Okay, things aren't how they
should be. I regret that I made that
mistake. I regret that I did that thing
that caused this bad thing to happen."
And my gosh, my friends, there's such a
scale to this. I mean, you could
literally have I'm not, you know, I'm
not going to say this, but like like any
level of regrets that like like on the
high end of the scale. Um
gosh, like if you killed somebody, okay,
I'm not going to say that like anybody
who's watching this, I hope that that's
not your story, but like yes, regret
that that happened, but learn to love
yourself enough to say, I can grow from
this. I can become a better person. I
can become a better version of myself. I
can become the version of myself that I
always want to do. And I mean that like
like some of y'all might be judging the
fact that I'm saying if somebody,
you know, did something horrible that
they should forgive themselves. But can
I tell you this?
Yes, there's consequences. Yes, those
are things that we should not do that
should not have happened.
But living in that regret is not going
to do you or anybody else any good. It's
time to forgive yourself. It's time to
grow from this. It's time to move on
from it. And what happens is when we can
truly move on from the things that we
regret, we can reinvent our lives. We
can become a better person.
You know, unfortunately, a lot of people
don't reinvent their lives. A lot of
people don't become a better person and
they're just going through the motions.
It's going to be hard work. It's going
to take some effort. You're going to
need counseling. You're going to need
guiding. You're going to need coaching.
You're going to need mentoring. If
you've been somebody who's been in
business and you've, you know, maybe you
lost a bunch of money in a business deal
or something like that, you're going to
need to work with a successful business
coach to get you back in the game doing
the stuff that you know you can do to
move past that regret that you feel,
that worry, that doubt, that insecurity,
and all of those things that go on
inside of us. Those are natural human
things that we deal with as a person
living on planet Earth. You're going to
end up dealing with them. It just
happens. It's just part of life. But we
can't let those things run us. We can't
let our regrets become our identity, our
personality,
and who we are. Sure, you can. You can
choose to, but you can also choose not
to. And that's what I want to encourage
you in is that no matter what regrets
you have, no matter what things that you
are feeling that you you don't want to
happen, that you didn't want to happen,
that you don't want to experience, that
you're upset that happened in your life,
can I tell you this? It doesn't have to
define you. It does not have to be your
forever story. It's a footnote on the
grand scheme of life that you are
creating and designing. And you have
control over your life, the life that
you're living, the life that you're
designing, the life that you're creating
for yourself and your family. And you
don't need to stay stuck
in the version
that you're existing in right now or
that has always been. the version that
regrets things, that replays these
things. And so, practically, one of the
things that you can do, this is
something like I've learned by working
with a therapist. I worked with a
therapist for a couple of years, is
realizing that like change what you're
focusing on. Change even the story that
you tell yourself and the memory. And
what ends up happening is you can
literally rewrite in your mind
the story of how things went.
And this changes
how you feel about them. For instance,
the story of the regret and the
situations that I feel, I told myself
from an outside looking in,
I was a traumatized young man that was
looking to alcohol for peace and freedom
because I didn't know and I was never
taught what to do and how to express
myself. But I was just looking for
attention any way that I could get it by
making stupid choices.
And that, my friends, gives me
compassion on that version of myself.
That version of myself that made those
mistakes, I have compassion on.
I'm able to say, you know what, like he
he was doing some stuff, but he was also
doing the best he could.
And and sure, I could have done better
and I did better, and I'm doing better,
right?
But in that moment, it comes from a
sense of self-love and self-compassion
that we truly grow. And that's what
creates the better version of ourselves.
It's when you love yourself enough to
say, you know what, what can I learn
from this?
How can I look at this from the
objective reality of, okay, here's what
happened, but it does not have to be my
forever story. Here's what led to that.
Here's what influenced that. I had,
okay, I'm gonna be real with y'all. I
had some crazy influence. The people I
was hanging around,
the people I even looked up to as
mentors were not healthy for me.
They were not helping me.
And my thinking was clouded by that.
Again, I'm not giving up responsibility.
I had to be responsible, right? I am
responsible for my actions.
I regret the actions that I made, but I
also look at it with compassion and I
say, you know what,
that that guy was doing doing the best
he could and and he and he's grown from
it. And I'm proud of the man that I've
become today. I reinvented myself, my
life, brick by brick. Every piece of
myself had to become remade new. And I
think, listen, we have versions of
ourselves that we're always reinventing
ourselves. We're remaking ourselves new
every single day, every single week.
Right now, I have a version of myself
that I'm literally rebuilding today of a
business owner, an investor, a father, a
husband that's I'm proud of, but I also
know the work that I need to do and I
know where I'm going. And it takes a
decision. I woke up this morning. I made
a decision. And I said, "You know what?
That version of me,
I'm walking in that now. I'm not making
excuses for why I can't or I shouldn't
or I'm not able to." And I'm telling
you, the productivity that comes out of
that when you make a decision
to finally stop living life based on our
excuses
and our feelings
and what's not going right. And we
decide, you know what? I'm going to be
the one that decides where I'm going,
what happens with my life, and what
becomes of that. When you do that, my
friends,
you get to change your life. You get to
decide your destiny, and you get to
steer everything that happens in your
life. And what ends up happening is, you
know, we hear about the law of
attraction and manifestation or things
like that. I think some of those things
the the real part about it is dialing
your brain in your thinking and then
what ends up happening is as you think
your actions follow and it starts to
create the life you envisioned.
And that's exactly what's happened to me
in my life. That's exactly what's
happened with my family, with my wife,
with our kids.
I have moments now where I will think a
thing and it will happen in my life. And
I believe that there is a spiritual
aspect to this as well. I believe that
the spiritual aspect of it
doesn't even matter your religious
background. Like my background is
Christian, but I believe that there is a
spiritual framework for how God created
the universe that if you come into
alignment and agreement
with good things happening and you start
declaring and you start believing and
you start speaking them, we start
speaking them into existence that that
literally things around us will start to
line up in our favor for things to
happen. I mean, I've seen it happen in
my life. I've seen it happen in the
mentors that I've worked with where they
lit like when you truly start aligning
your life and you start reinventing
yourself, you will start to see that the
stuff that you declare and speak into
reality will start to happen for you.
It will start to happen for you. And
it's not like it's not like I'm going to
speak in like like a magic, you know,
rabbit out of a hat, but it will come to
pass
in in in ways that we never expected.
It's always how we never expected.
But it but it but it happens and it
comes together and literally we start
designing and creating our life where we
thought that we were living in the back
seat and we were a victim. Now we are
victorious and we are the designer, the
co-creator of our life with God to
create stuff. That's what I truly
believe and that's that's my belief
about those things. So anyways, listen,
I hope this has encouraged you. I hope
this has helped you.
I believe if you apply what I taught in
this lesson, in this training, you will
see a change in your life like you never
imagined. We'll talk soon everybody.
Have a good one.